I-Da Chiang

E-mail: idchiang@asiaa.sinica.edu.tw | LinkedIn: idchiang

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Dust Life Cycle & Interstellar Medium

I am interested in studying the evolution of interstellar dust with multiwavelength observations. One of my projects is measuring the spatially resolved dust-to-metals ratio in the nearby galaxies, and interpreting the results with dust chemical evolution models, simulations and ancillary data.

HI 21 cm Line & Radio Astronomy

The distribution of neutral gas is a key element in dust sciences and cold gas dynamics. The $\rm Hi~21~cm$ line traces neutral hydrogen atoms in the ISM. I reduced new $\rm Hi~21cm$ line data of $\sim \! \! 30$ galaxies observed by VLA with CASA. These new data allows us to construct a new dust-to-metals ratio survey in the nearby galaxies.

EMPLOYMENT

Institute of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Academia Sinica

2021 - Current

Postdoc Fellow

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2021

Graduate Research Assistant

- Built a python-based toolkit for dust SED fitting and multi-wavelength data analysis.
- Analyzed the dust-to-gas and dust-to-metal ratios in the spiral galaxy M101.
- Analyzed the dust-to-metal ratio and CO-to- H_2 conversion factor in detail in \sim 50 nearby galaxies.
- Examined the empirical radiation distribution law and the turbulent power spectrum in the local group galaxies with the dust SED fitting tools.
- Reduced HI 21cm line data of \sim 30 galaxies observed by VLA with the Common Astronomy Software Applications package (CASA).

University of California San Diego

2014 - 2016

Teaching Assistant (TA) and Lab TA Coordinator

- Familiarized new teaching assistants with lab setups and teaching skills.
- Led discussion sessions, which helped ~ 40 students each week.
- Led introductory level physics lab, with 24 students per session.
- Improved course materials from feedback from teaching assistants and students.

National Taiwan University

2012 - 2014

Graduate Research Assistant

- Improved the photo-degradation reactor for wastewater treatment with plasmonic nano-particles.
- Built the protocol for maintaining/using the sputter machine and clean room.

Taiwan (R.O.C.) Armed Forces

2011 - 2012

Second Lieutenant (Company second-in-command)

EDUCATION

niversity of California San Diego h.D. (Physics and Astronomy) hesis: "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies" dviser: Prof. Karin M. Sandstrom	2014 - 2021 2012 - 2014
National Taiwan University M.S. (Physics) Thesis: "Plasmonic Enhanced Optical Disk Reactor for Wastewater Treatment" Adviser: Prof. Din Ping Tsai	
National Taiwan University B.S. (Physics) TEACHING EXPERIENCE	2007 - 2011
Lab TA Coordinator, PHYS 1-ABC Lab – UCSD	2015 - 2016
Teaching Assistant, PHYS 1-A Lab – UCSD	2014 - 2015

REFEREED PUBLICATIONS (AS FIRST OR SECOND AUTHOR)

- 4) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, E. Koch, K. Kreckel, A.K. Leroy, A. Schruba, D. Utomo, T. Williams, "Resolving the Dust-to-Metals Ratio and CO-to-H₂ Conversion Factor in the Nearby Universe", 2021, ApJ, 907, 29.
- 3) E.W. Koch, **I-D. Chiang**, D. Utomo, J. Chastenet, A.K. Leroy, E.W. Rosolowsky, K.M. Sandstrom, "Spatial power spectra of dust across the Local Group: No constraint on disc scale height", 2020, MN-RAS, 492, 2663.
- 2) D. Utomo, I-D. Chiang, A.K. Leroy, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, "The Resolved Distributions of Dust Mass and Temperature in Local Group Galaxies", 2019, ApJ, 874, 141.
- 1) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, L.C. Johnson, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, "The Spatially Resolved Dust-to-metals Ratio in M101", 2018, ApJ, 865, 117.

A full list of refereed publications at ADS Public Library is available here.

OBSERVING TIME AWARDED AS P.I.

The Very Large Array (2022B), "Connecting Gas and Dust: Mapping HI in 7 Herschel Galaxies", 28 hours 2022

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

Colloquium, "Multiwavelength observations of dust, gas, and metals in the $z\sim 0$ universe", NCU, Taoyuan, Taiwan

Contributed talk, "Dust, gas, and metals: Observing Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies", Galaxy Evolution Workshop 2021, NAOJ, Tokyo, Japan 2021

Colloquium, "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Taiwan

Contributed talk, "Dust, gas and metals: Resolving the Dust Life Cycle in the Nearby Universe", The AAS 235th Meeting, Honolulu, USA

Special seminar, "Dust-to-Metals Relation in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Taiwan

2019

Poster, ASROC2019, Taichung, Taiwan	2019
Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Galaxies", Du Universe, Tucson, USA	usting the 2019
Lunch talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA	2019
Tea time talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA	2018
Poster, CPHDUST, Copenhagen, Denmark	2018
Poster, ASROC2018, Kinmen, Taiwan	2018
Lunch talk, UCSD, San Diego, USA	2018
OUTREACH EXPERIENCE	
Student seminar @ ASIAA – lecturer	2021
Research in physics workshop for community college students @ UCSD – lecturer	2021
Python workshop for physics undergrads @ UCSD – presenter	2019
Life as a scientist @ Jianguo High School – lecturer	2019
STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights @ San Diego, USA – presenter	2018
Tech Trek @ UCSD – presenter	2017
Physics GRE bootcamp @ UCSD – teaching assistant	2016
AWARDS	
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2014
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2011
Presidential Award, National Taiwan University	2011